Bryan Leighton

Full Stack Web Developer

bryan.leigh77@gmail.com	
-------------------------	--

+49 151 6 874 6342

Berlin, Germany

linkedin.com/in/bryanleighton77 in

github.com/bdlb77 🦪

I am a highly motivated person who has profound experience in work under extreme pressure, and great adaptability to any situation that is presented. Having served in a military that is not of my native tongue, while also learning medical terminology and techniques in a foreign language, I have learned that my strength is my ability to persevere through any hardship and realizing that nothing is ever impossible to accomplish.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant

Le Wagon Coding Bootcamp

07/2018 – Present

Israel, Germany

– Assist students learning full-stack web development

Contact: Clara Morgeneyer - +49 178 2004 525

Egoz Special Operations Unit Combat Medic

Israel Defense Forces

11/2015 - 05/2018

Israel

- Company Medical Commander
- Special Operations Combat Medic First Sergeant
- Active Combat Medic on deployment in hostile zones
- Active First Responder to all civilian emergencies within zone
- Led First Aid and medical trainings within the Company

Law Intern for Criminal Defense Attorney

Jimmy Parks Law Office

06/2012 – 08/2012 San Antonio, USA

- Conducted and led extensive document review projects
- Developed strategies and arguments in preparation for presentation of cases
- Comprehensive analysis over client backgrounds

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development

Le Wagon Coding Bootcamp

04/2018 – 06/2018 Tel Aviv, Israel

HTML/ CSSRuby on RailsPostgreSQL

B.A. International Relations and Global Studies

University of Texas at Austin

08/2012 - 05/2015 3.37/4.0

Middle Eastern SudiesFrenchInternational Security

Concentration in European Union studies

Sciences Po - Exchange

07/2013 – 12/2013 Paris, France

EU Strategic StudiesU.S. Foreign Policy

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Forget Me Not (06/2018 - 06/2018) ♂

- 2-week final project during coding bootcamp. Business networking web app
- http://forgetmenot.network

LEADERSHIP

Israel Defense Forces Special Operations Detachment

Company Medical Commander / Squad Commander

UT Austin Rugby (10/2014 – 05/2015)

Events and Activities Officer

UT Austin pro-Israel advocacy organization: Texans for Israel (09/2013 – 05/2014)

VP of programming and content

LANGUAGES

English Hebrew
Native or Bilingual Proficiency Full Professional Proficiency

French German

Limited Working Proficiency Elementary Proficiency

INTERESTS

